As a logical, innovative problem solver with extensive management experience and strong customer service skills, I am seeking a full-stack software engineering position where I can use my technical skills and drive to make a positive impact. I have developed and implemented new service strategies that have increased customer growth and satisfaction by 30%, and I am committed to making the most of available resources to achieve continued growth and results.

Technical Skills

- Proficient in Java, SQL, PostgreSQL, JQuery, Spring Boot, MVC, JSON, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Vue.is, Vueitfy is, IntelliJ, VCS, responsive design, GIt, unit testing, integration testing, C#, and network support
- Exposure to C#, Objective-C, TypeScript, Linux, React, Angular and AWS
- Bilingual in Spanish (able to read, write, and speak fluently)
- Skilled in QuickBooks, Excel, and medical terminology and records, including CPT9 and IDC-10 coding,
- Hold a 2-15 Life, Health, and Annuities license.

Technical Experience

Project Scheduler App: Developed a project management app for Frontline Advisory Group using Java backend. Jdbc, PostgreSQL database, and Vue.js frontend framework. Implemented features such as CRUD projects, schedules, statuses, user registration, password changes, and approval for administrators.

Venmo Money transfer app: Worked on a team using Java and SQL to create a Venmo-like money transfer app that connects to a server-side database and allows users to access, store and update data. Utilized Java, Jdbc, Spring Boot, Postman, PostgreSQL, Git, MVC models, RESTful API server, JSON Web Tokens for authentication and authorization.

Jframes Snake Game: Created a Snake game using Java and J-Frames, demonstrating proficiency in object-oriented programming. The game allows users to control a snake that consumes apples on the screen, with the score increasing by one for each apple consumed.

Vue.js Weather app: Developed a weather app using Vue.js framework and the open weather API to make calls to a RESTful API and return current weather data.

CLI Vending Machine: Created a simulated vending machine with an integrated inventory tracking system and owner print-out function for orders, transactions, and maintenance. Utilized OOP principles, unit testing, and file I/O.

Education

Tech Elevator, National Live Remote (Full-Stack Developer Bootcamp)

Jul 2022- Oct 2022

Completed a 14-week full-stack coding Bootcamp learning how to create dynamic web-based software systems using Java and providing 800+ hours of development education and application. (Java, SQL, HTML, CSS, Vue.is)

Florida International University - B.S. Computer Science

Jan 2020 - Expected completion 2024

(notable completed courses: Calculus 3, Differential Equations, Discrete Mathematics, Physics 2 W/Calc For engineers)

Professional Experience

Frontline Advisory Group: Austin, TX (Remote) **Full-Stack Software Engineer**

Sep 2022

I worked with a 4-person SCRUM team in the development of an internal project management web tool for standardizing data gathering, analyzing schedules, and automating reports and dashboards. The tool is used by consultants to monitor project schedules, and collect baseline schedules, up-to-date monthly schedules, change orders, and root causes analysis.

FYZICAL Therapy and Balance Centers: Margate, FL

Mar 2014 - Present

Software Developer, Director of Marketing, M.D Liaison, Administrator, Medical Biller

- Developed patient portal, landing site, and insurance portal as a node is server to validate accepted insurance.
- As a system administrator, increased patient growth by 30% through SEO and developed marketing strategies for a physical therapy office.

Office of Dr. Bose Yalamanchi(Cosmetic Surgery): Coral Springs, FL

Nov 2016 - 2018

Medical Assistant, Surgical Technician

Assisted the doctor with scheduling and updates, sterilized surgical equipment and supplies, and provided detailed insight to patients about the process and procedure of their upcoming surgery.